Last time, you saw how to use marker size and
上节课中 你看到如何在散点图里用
shape to encode third variables into scatter plots.
大小和形状对第三个变量进行编码
The more natural encoding supported by both Matplot and Seaborn however is color.
实际上 Matplotlib 和 Seaborn 提供的更方便的编码方式其实是颜色
For categorical data, we can use
对于分类数据 我们可以使用
Seaborn's facet grid and set the hue argument to our column of choice.
Seaborn 的 FacetGrid 函数 将 hue 参数设置为想要绘制的列名
In the Mat method, we set the regplot function and our access variables.
在 map 函数中 我们传入 regplot 函数以及坐标轴变量
Additional red plot parameters are still set afterwards.
之后设置其他的 regplot 参数
Let's make a few tweaks to the plot.
让我们来对这个图表进行一些调整
First, let's change the order in which the levels are plotted so
首先 调整类别数据的绘制顺序
that the manual transmission points are plotted on top of automatic.
使手动挡的数据点 绘制在自动挡的数据点上面
We set this through the hue order parameter in facet grid.
这可以通过 FacetGrid 里的 hue_order 参数来实现
Note that this is not just plain order since
要注意的是该参数名没有用 order 这个单独的单词
facet grid can also take orderings on other facet dimensions.
因为 FacetGrid 也可以在其他维度上设置 order (比如 row_order、col_order)
Since we have only one plot,
因为我们只有一个图表
let's also increase its size.
所以可以适当地增加图表大小
Setting size equals four and aspect equals 1.5 gives us a larger plot,
将 size 设为4 将 aspect 设为 1.5
50 percent longer than it is tall.
长比宽多两倍多
Finally, let's use the facet grid object method
最后 我们使用 FacetGrid 对象的 add_legend 方法
add legend to automatically add a legend to the plot.
来自动添加图例
Transmission type is a nominal type variable,
变速器类型属于无序分类变量
so the default qualitative palette works great.
所以默认的分类调色板就很合适
What if we plotted by vehicle class instead?
如果绘制车辆类型呢？
Vehicle class is an ordered variable,
车辆类型是一个有序变量
so the qualitative palette doesn't work quite as well.
所以分类调色板并不是很适用
We should specify a sequential palette instead.
我们应该使用有序调色板
This can be set through facet grids palette parameter.
可以通过 FacetGrid 的 palette 参数进行设置
We can use the same strings as in Matplotlib.
可以使用 Matplotlib 的调色板字符串
I'll use viridis_r in this case.
在这里 我们使用 viridis_r 调色板
This palette not only goes from light to dark,
这个调色板不仅包括颜色的深浅
but it also has a good range of hues to further discriminate the categorical variables.
而且也包含不同的色调以区分不同类别的变量
What if we have a numeric variable instead, like CO2 emissions?
那如果我们现在要绘制数值变量呢？比如二氧化碳的排放量
We should not just set the variable in the hue parameter since
这次不能直接在 hue 参数上修改变量名称了
facet grid only expects to facet across categorical variables.
因为 FacetGrid 函数只针对分类变量
If we do that, otherwise we get a messy legend with one color
如果我们这么做了 我们会得到一个很长的而且
for every unique CO2 value in a rank ordered color scheme.
每个单独的数值都占用了一种颜色的图例
Instead, we should just use the basic Matplotlib scatter function to create our plot.
我们应该使用基础 Matplotlib 里面的 scatter函数来绘图
We lose the convenient jitter in this case,
虽然不是很便捷
but there is an interaction in the color parameters in
但是设置颜色参数的灵活度提高了
red plot that make coloring by value hard to do.
这是 regplot 函数做不到的
With scatter, adding a third numeric variable via color is as simple as setting
使用 scatter 函数 只需将在 c 参数中设置第三个数值变量
the C parameter and different color palettes are set through the Cmap parameter.
在 cmap 参数中设置调色板
I used the colorbar function to add a color bar to the plot,
我使用了 colorbar 函数在图表中添加了一个颜色条
and I add a label parameter to provide the color map units.
并且用 label 参数在颜色条上方添加了单位注释